SUMMARY

Full-stack engineer with 10 years' experience in web development and 3 years' experience leading teams. Led Under Armour's backend platform team, delivering a < 2s page load time for US and CA websites, improving customer conversions and experience. Passionate about performance, security, and tooling.

SKILLS

- Typescript/Javascript, Node.js, Next.js, React, GraphQL, REST, OpenAPI, Swagger, Git, Github Actions
- Postgres, DynamoDB, S3, Redis, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, AWS, Datadog, Jenkins, Agile, Kanban
- VS Code, VIM, Postman, JIRA, Confluence, Salesforce Commerce Cloud, Salesforce Marketing Cloud

EXPERIENCE

Under Armour (E-Commerce)

Manager - Backend Platform Team

09/2022 - 10/2024

- Managed a team of ~10 engineers owning all Under Armour backend micro-services for US/CA websites and iOS and Android mobile apps
- Expanded backend API support to Canada and other international websites for <2s page load times
- Moved team to continuous delivery model with Github Actions, feature flagging, and <3m build times
- Created/owned on-call rotation, backend internal support ticketing, and production alerting
- Supported all feature teams in architecture/design/delivery of all changes to website experience

Tech Lead - Backend Platform Team

01/2022 - 09/2022

- Lead backend effort to support Next.js/Vercel frontend for <2s page load times
- Migrated payment provider from Paymetric to Aurus for credit card payments and added Klarna support
- Provided architectural guidance, oversight, and coding for delivery of UA's Loyalty program
- Integrated backend with Manhattan Active Omni order history and return APIs for customer self-service

Senior Software Engineer - Shop App Team

10/2018 - 01/2022

- Built Node.js, Typescript GraphQL API powering checkout/grids/product details for the mobile apps
- Delivered backend for new features like express Apple Pay checkout, Shop App exclusives, preorders

Springbox (Digital Marketing Agency)

Senior Software Engineer

02/2017 - 10/2018

- Full-stack work building client websites and applications under aggressive timelines with small teams:
 - Website for managing family divorce proceedings

(Node.js w/ React, Postgres, AWS)

o IoT for tracking loading dock metrics with dashboards and alerts

(Lambdas, Laravel, DynamoDB) (C# MVC, Bootstrap, AWS)

O Website for finding rural real estate properties and loans

(Node.js w/ React, Ruby on Rails)

Example store-front documentation for e-commerce vendor
Experience updates and SQL reports for pancreatic cancer trials web-site

(C# ASP.NET, MSSQL)

Compass Learning (Ed-Tech)

01/2015 - 02/2017

DevOps Engineer

 Created builds/automated jobs/tests/environments and infrastructure for ETL processes running on multiple microservices to offboard from a costly vendor and cut ETL runtimes from hours to minutes

EDUCATION

Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science